Guide to the Yale Student Papers Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- History of Art senior essays, 1987-2000; Accession 2009-A-042
  - Peacock, Sally S.: Twentieth Century Representationsof Shaker Furniture, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Go, Karen M.: Virginia Woolf and Vanessa Bell, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Hayes, Tanya M.: Problemof the Idealized Female Nude in Post 1945 American Art, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Moorhead, Jasmine: Making Me Thinking Me, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Curtis, Celia: Classic Mimbres Animal Imagery from New Mexico's Swarts Ruin, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Choi, Bong- Seok: The Sosaku Hanga Movement, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Christensen, Gustavus: Visual Conflict and Sexual Tension in the Paintingof Sam Francis, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Brecken: Solving the Mystery, Rediscovering the Vatican Laocoon Group, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Lobb, Annelena: Afrocubanism and Cuban National Idenity, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Reddy, Sam: John Quidor's Leatherstocking Meets the Law, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Phillips, Glenn: Minimal Truths: Art, Knowledge Discourse, and the Cube, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Smooke, Ellen: Colonel John Trumbull Miniature Portraits, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Maksrivorawan, Bhohathai: Reinterpretationsof Traditional Buddhism in Contemporary Thai Art, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Havenon, Alieda de: The Roleof Nature in Japanese Lacquer and Tiffany Japanesque Silver, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Hudson, Ben H: Unveiling the Paradoxof Realism, Thomas Eakins' Imagesof African-Americans, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Go, Karen M.: Virginia Woolf and Vanessa Bell, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Breuer, Marcel: Modernity in the Eyesof a Humanist, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Bockstoce, John Grimston: The Revolutionary Architectureof James Gamble Rogers at Yale, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Dana: Vertner Woodson Tandy, Architect, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Benton, Catherine Luden: The Migrationof the Negro, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Chow, Colin Kuo-Lung: Searching for Identity in Contemporary Asian American Art, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Kee, Joan: Subverting the Slant, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Jo, Michael: Gloucester Cathedral, the Perpendicular Style, and the Memoryof Edward II, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Daria M.: The Museumof Modern Art and the Entanglementof Architecture, Competition and Exhibition, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Natelson, Rachel: Ad Reinhardt Consumateoutsideror Reluctant Insider, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Alsdorf, Bridget: The View from the Gondola, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Susan E.: Walking the Walk, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Popoff, Tessie: The Placeof Astrology in 16th and 17th Century English Architecture, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Eleey, Peter: The Embodied Copy, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Hochstim, Christian: Text, Symbol and the four Creatures in Insular Illuminations, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Urena, Leslie J.: The Spanish Reconquista and the Exchanges between Christians, Jews and Muslims, 1999 (Box 2)
  - McCarthy, Alice: Symbolic Landscapes, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Rapp, Alyssa: From COBRA to Clemente, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Errico, Melissa: Three Tarocchi Packs by Bonifacio Bembo and his atelier, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Kingery, Anne: Glensfoot A Villa, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Perrin, Julian: Sir John Soane and the Aestheticof Ruins, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Baker, Louise Holland: The Resurrectionof Traditional Music in Post-Colonial Ireland, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Merjian, Ara H.: Violence, Voyeurism, and the Politicsof Witnessing, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Cipolla, Nicholas: The Imperial Childrenof Antonine and Severan Dynasties in Portraiture and Literature, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Perkowski, Sara E.: The Long March to Modernity, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Dorment, Lily: Housing Politics, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lyons, Camilla L.: Processed Identity (De)Constructionof Chuck Close's Photography-based Portraits, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Anthony James: Furniture Advertisement in the 1950's, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Karnasiewicz, Sarah: The Colorsof the Spirit, 1998 (Box 2)
  - o'Donnell, Matt: The Memorializationof the African Burial Ground (Box 2)
  - Tilghman, Lindley: Martin Munkacsi the New Photographer, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Evans, Sarah Jennings: Existentialism in the Artof Albert Ryder, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lyall, Victoria: The Diadoumenos by Polykleitos, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Beck, Marcelle: Georges De La Tour and Caravaggio, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Drabkin, Andrew: Southern Fried Schinkle, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Wangensteen, Kjell: An Existential Readingof Three Works by George Tooker, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Brisman, Shira: Edward Burne-Jones and the Romanceof Labor, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Beck, Marcelle: Georges De La Tour and Caravaggio, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Lobb, Annelena: Afrocubanism and Cuban National Idenity, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bustamante, Celina Elizabeth: Death, Revolution and the Popular Imagination, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Perrin, Julian: Sir John Soane and the Aestheticof Ruins, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Sobel, Emily: Georgiao'Keefe At Home, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Cipolla, Nicholas: The Imperial Childrenof Antonine and Severan Dynasties in Portraiture and Literature, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Eleey, Peter: The Embodied Copy, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bolz, Bonnie Alyssa: The Beautiful and the Beastly Erotic Drawingsof Gustav Vigeland, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Strauss, Bernarda: Klimt and Schiele, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Lee, Pamela Margot: Zen in the Art pf Abstract Expressionism, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Elizabeth: Continuity and Change Five Contemporary Chinese Artists, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Sexton, James: Lowland Framing Influenceson the Pre-1750 Domestic Architectureof Coastal Connecticut, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Meyer, Richard: Artistic Immunity Illustrations, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Meyer, Richard: Artistic Immunity, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Hollister, John: New Haven's City Beautiful Movement, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Abernathy, Pauline: Jan Steen and the Festive Scence, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Wilson, Shelley: Still Life, Celebration, Seduction and Threat, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Tobler, Henry: The Appropriationof Signs andobjects, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Rubin, Lara: De Chirico and Turin, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Spreitzer, Jennifer: Multifaceted Charles IVof Bohemia, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Schaffer, Sara: Francesco Cangiullo Simply a Poet, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Bodow, Steven: Architectural Programof Yale President Whitney Griswold, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Crowley, Kathleen A. The Governor Ingersoll House, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Donohue, Stacy: Edward Hopper's Western Motel, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, Kendra: The Artof Dreaming, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Barker, Elizabeth: Angelica Kauffman and the Royal Academyof Arts, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Rohan, Timothy: Salvator Rosa's Influenceon Arists and Writers in Romantic England, 1990 (Box 4)
  - McNamara, Denis: The Divine Idea to Man, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Rosenbaum, David: Toward a New Urban Vision Battery Park New York City, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Wittman, Richard: The Genesisof Burgundian Gothic Architecture, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Ewing, Heather: An Architectural Historyof the Nation Zoological Park, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Erlebacher, Jonah: Light, Shade and Form in Fifteenth Century Italian Art, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Cramer, Peter: The Art that Wasn't at the Met, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Errico, Melissa: Three Tarocchi Packs by Bonifacio Bembo and his atelier, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Stephan, Annelisa: Gerhard Richter and Recent German Painting, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Richbourg, Eli: The Momentous Hour, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Dilks, Christina: Saint Apollinaris in Ravenna, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Jennifer Renzi, The Structureof Vision in Eric Rohmer's Summer, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Westcott, Valerie: The Creationof the Modern Auction House, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Taylor, John: The Wupatki Ballcourt, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Nygren, Anthony: The Functionof Form, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Kousser, Rachel: Death, Art, Daily Life: An Essay in the Interpretationof Classical Athenian White-ground Lekythoi, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Kahn, Elizabeth Sarah: Homeward Bound Scenesof Homer'sodysseyon Ancient Greek Pottery, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Kuenzli, Katherine: Lalique and the Decorative Arts, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Taback, Natalie: A Lexiconof Chevrons: Secondary Motifson Greek Pottery, 1994 (Box 5)
  - White, Elizabeth: Continuity and Change in Martin Scorsese's The Ageof Innocence, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Rogers, Amy: Considerationsof Power, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Fox, Emily: An Interpretationof Velazquez's Las Hilanderasor The Weavers, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Dodds, Seth: Consequencesof A Context-Oriented Philosophy, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Ross, Elizabeth: The Receptionof the Renaissance in Bavaria: Plaques and Plaquettes, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Armstrong, Naja: Meeting Hallsof the Greek World and theoriginsof the Roman Basilica, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Tsutsumi, Rachel: The Text and Image Relationship in Two 12th Century Japanese Handscrolls, 1994 (Box 5)
- Swett, Brooks, "A Portrait of the Webster Family During the Civil War" [computer file], 2008; Accession 2009-A-072
  Written for John Gaddis' seminar "The Art of Biography."
  - Swett, Brooks, "A Portrait of the Webster Family During the Civil War", 2008; computer file (PDF)
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2008; Accession 2009-A-121
  - Bonvillian, Raphael, "Caught in the Middle: An American Perspective on Ethnic Responses to Chinese and Soviet Influence in Xin Jiang, 1944-1951", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Zachary, "Yale Student Disorder in Revolutionary America, 1750-1780", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Casertano, Tyler, "From Hero to Zero: The Volatile and Often Inaccurate Representation of Charles A. Lindbergh", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chaloff, Scott, "Dynamite Tonight: Vietnam On and Off-Stage at the Yale School of Drama, 1966-1969", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Winner of the 2008 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize on Yale
  - Cotter, Mark P., "Community Progress, Inc. and the New Haven African American Community: A Well Intentioned But Failed War on Poverty", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Duboff, Josh, "'Do Write Oftener': The Power and Politics of Letters in the Civil War", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Freemark, Yonah, "Roosevelt Island: Exception to a City in Crisis", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Glickstein, Jed, "After Midnight: The Circuit Judges and the Repeal of the Judiciary Act of 1808", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Goldstein, Matthew, "What the Failures of the Lindsay and Bloomberg Congestion Plans Tell Us About Transportation Policy and the Mayoralty of New York City", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Peterson, Jason, "Yale and World War II", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Suich, Alexandra E., "Faith, Fervor, and Failure: The Evolution of Dr. Peter Parker's Diplomacy with China, 1841-1857", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vanderbilt, Sarah, "Equal Partners in Peace: The Long Shadow of World War I Women's Activism, 1915-1950", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Weiner, Aaron, "Hiram Bingham's Expeditions and the Peruvian Response: A Connecticut Yanqui in the Land of the Incas", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Winner of the 2007 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest for Yale
- Olivia Martinez, "On Broadway: A Timeline of New Haven Business" [computer file], 2008; Accession 2009-A-122
  - Paper hard copy of digital original (Box 1)
- Shannon Lee Connors, "New Haven and the American City: Visual Representation of the City, Wooster Square" [computer file], 2008 October 8; Accession 2009-A-132
  - Shannon Lee Connors, "New Haven and the American City: Visual Representation of the City, Wooster Square", 2008 October 8; 1
    - Use copy (Box 1)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2009; Accession 2010-A-013
  - Bowie, Nikolas, "Class Warfare, Inc.: James L. Buckley and the Conservative Origins of Corporate Class Consciousness in the 1970s", 2009; 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, Colin, "The Biography of John Hall Paxon, U.S. Consul to Tihwa, 1946-1949: Hard Place, Soft Power", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapman, Emma W., "The Planner's Choice: Union Station and Its Relationship to the City of New Haven", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Handler, Nicholas Aaron, "Respectability and Radicalism: Harry Weinberger, the Jewish Left, and the Fight for Free Speech", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kramer, Maxwell A., "Soldiers and Statesmen of the Atomic Age: A Look at Revisionist History of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and an Apologia of the Man Who Dropped the Bomb", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lin, Jennifer K., "From Chemical Terror to Clinical Trial: The Development of Chemotherapy at Yale in World War II", 2009; 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Winner of the 2009 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize on Yale
  - Maldonado, Roger, "New Haven's Failed Revitalization Efforts in the 1960s: Community Building Not Incorporated", 2009; 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Michel, Kevin, "A Struggle Between Brothers: A Re-Examination of the Idea of a Cohesive Conservative Movement Through the Intellectual Life and Personal Conflict Surrounding L. Brent Bozell", 2009; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Winner of the 2009 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize on MSSA research
  - Parks, Anna Legant, "Polio Across the Iron Curtain: Dorothy M. Horstmann's 1959 Evaluation of the Sabine Polio Vaccine Trial in the U.S.S.R.", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - St. Jean, Emily, "Louise Bryant: A Reconsideration", 2009; 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tallevi, Ashley, "The Cause of Labor: Rose Pastor Stokes' Ideology Odyssey", 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Wipfler, Anna, "The Making of the 'Gay Ivy': A History of Lesbian and Gayu Student Organizing at Yale, 1969-1987", 2009; 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wiznia, Lauren, "The GI Bill and Yale: Tradition Under Challenge", 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Yergin, Rebecca, "The Turning Point: Ogden Rogers Reid's Ambassadorship to Israel, 1959-1961", 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Young, Christopher M., "Politicalization in Colonial Education: American Colleges React to Revolution: Yale and King's Colleges, 1740-1777", 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2010; Accession 2011-A-024
  - Bewley, Elizabeth, "Feminist Support of the Black Panther Party, 1969-1971: 'Free Our Sisters, Free Ourselves!'", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brusalis, Christopher, "The Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York: Refining Definitions of Success and Failure in Healthcare Reform", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapman, Dora de Kenessey, "Louise Bryant and the Radical Woman: Feminism, Socialism and the Russian Revolution as Seen Through the Work of Louise Bryant", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Flores, Krystal, "LaCasa, Mi Casa: Providing a Home for Puerto Ricans at Yale, 1971-1977", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fraga, Sean, "'Two Days By Plane': America's First Transcontonental Passenger Airline and the Selling of the Skies", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gottesdiener, Laura, "'We Must Take Over the Means of Production to Create Our Own Meanings': Riot Grrrl and Homocore Zines Rewriting Gender and Sexuality", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Iscoe, Mark, "Chester Bowles in India: A Defender of Freedom", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Janowitz, Sophia, "'Don't Imitate Life. Live': The Interplay of Theater and Living in the Living Theatre's Fall 1968 Performances at Yale", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kehl, Danielle Leah, "The Buckley-Coffin Crusade: Preaching the Gospel of Political Ideology to Yale and America in the 1960s., 2010 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kembaiyan, Vivek, "The Number One Question: Chester Bowles Confronts the American Race Record in India, 1951-1953", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lupien, Hannah, "Sharing Their Culture with the Uncultured: Women, Immigrants, and Food in Progressive Era New Haven", 2020 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Regan, Eileen M., " The History of the Young Mothers Program of New Haven: Designing a Clinic to Treat the Patient and Not Just the Problem", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sanchez, Allen James, "One Part Student, One Part Worker, Zero Parts Recognized: The Creation of a Student Workforce and the Conflict Over Union Recognition in the GESO Campaign at Yale", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sangueza, Edith, "Imagining Modernity, Inventing Antiquity: Photography and Peruvian Landscape, 1870-1915", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Siegal, Sarah, "The Convergence of Civil Rights and Health Advocacy: The Establishment of New Haven's Hill Health Center", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Werner, Jennifer, "Theater and Society in Gilded Age America: The Life of Neil Burgess and the Women He Played", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Zaragova, Laura, "The Politicization of the Domestic Sphere: Female Consumption, Production, and hosehold Administration During the American Revolution", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mett, R. Michael, "An Historical Study of Propaganda and Group Structure within the Spanish Anarcho-Syndicalist Movement", 1961 May 1; Accession 2011-A-057
  - Mett, R. Michael, "An Historical Study of Propaganda and Group Structure within the Spanish Anarcho-Syndicalist Movement", 1961 May 1 (Box 1, Folder system_indicator_4b15629de84a9da863aabcc24480092e)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2011; Accession 2012-A-066
  - Boakye, Lorraine, "A Comparison of the Political Regimes of Kwame Nkumrah and J.J. Rawlings in Ghana, 1951-2001: The Redeemer vs. The Serial Coup Maker", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cohen, Haley, "Paved with Good Intentions: A Missionary Son and the Road to Hawaiian Annexation", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gipson, Lawrence West, "Religions of Elihu: The Integration of Catholic, Jews and Muslims into Protestant Yale", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lerman-Tan, Yinshi, "Theodore Winthrop: Experience, Space, and Memory", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Levin, Joshua, "Walter Lippmann and His Jewish Problem", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Magoon, Christopher, "The Yale-New Haven Education Corporation: A Case Study in the Limits of Liberalism, 1964-1970", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miller, Zeke, "The Education of Joe Lieberman: A Profile in Senatorial Independence", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nie, Sissi, "The Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission: The Myth of Bi-Nationalism", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scrudato, John, "Evangelizing for China: The Campaign Against Japanese Aggression in China by Missionary Pressure Groups, 1938-1941", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Spinks, Jenna, "Containment Consensus: The Impact of Europe and Two World Wars on the 1947 Policy Views of Walter Lippmann and George F. Keenan", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stone, Daniel, "Put a Nickel on the Drum, Save Another Drunken Bum: Harry B. Fisher and the Legacy of Prohibition at Yale", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Winner of the 2011 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest on Yale
  - Tannen, Joshua, "Making the Case for Privacy: Potter Stewart and the Fourth Amendment", 2011 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Winner of the 2011 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest for MSSA research
- Winning essays from the Manuscripts and Archives Diane E. Kaplan senior essay contest, 2012-2014; Accession 2015-A-049
  - Ross, Brendan, "From Practical Woodsman to Professional Forester: Henry S. Graves and the Professionalism of Forestry in the United States, 1900-1920", 2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Winner of the 2013 Manuscripts and Archives Diane E. Kaplan senior essay prize for MSSA research
  - Zelinsky, Nathaniel, "Who Governed Yale? Kingman Brewster and Higher Education in the 1970s", 2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Winner of the 2013 Manuscripts and Archives Diane E. Kaplan senior essay prize on Yale
  - Coe-Scharff, Jonah, ""New Roads" in Leftist Thought: Dwight MacDonald, Lewis Cosner and the Postwar Crisis of American Marxism", 2014 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Winner of the 2014 Manuscripts and Archives Diane E. Kaplan senior essay prize for MSSA research
  - Doyle, John (Jack), "Measuring Problems of Human Behavior: The Eugenic Origins of Yale's Institute of Psychology, 1921-1929", 2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Winner of the 2014 Manuscripts and Archives Diane E. Kaplan senior essay prize on Yale